<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes" ?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Projects on Udani A. Wijewardhana</title>
    <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Projects on Udani A. Wijewardhana</description>
    <generator>Source Themes Academic (https://sourcethemes.com/academic/)</generator>
    <language>en-us</language>
    
	    <atom:link href="https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    
    
    <item>
      <title>Analysis of incentive scheme of a reputed shoe company Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/clsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/clsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;CLSA is the sole distributor of all factories and other brands of footwear and other related products. Lorry loads of goods are being received and dispatched to various locations employing number of employees. There is an incentive system to motivate employees to expedite loading, sorting, unloading etc. which was not effective.The aim of this research is to build a better incentive scheme to improve the efficiency and productivity of the employees. Monte Carlo Simulation and train a Neural Network was used for this purpose through existing details.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of climate on species counts of the locally threatened Hooded Plover on the Mornington Peninsula using citizen science data</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/zim/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/zim/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;The Hooded Plover is a resident shorebird in Australia which is listed as a vulnerable bird species under the IUCN red list assessment criteria EPBC Act 1999. In this study our aim is to identify the effect of climate for Hooded Plover on Mornington Peninsula on a spatial and temporal scale. In order to clarify the effect of climate on the persistence of the Hooded Plover we have used validated citizen science data available in eBird Australia. To quantify any effects of climate, we have considered average temperature and rainfall for each season from 2010 to 2019. Citizen science count data often includes excess zeros for rare species like the Hooded Plover in specific areas or time periods. Therefore, we have considered the most common zero inflation models using Negative Binomial distributions and allowing for a spatio-temporal data structure. The performance of the Negative Binomial Hurdle model was found to be superior for all the models considered. The changes in seasonal patterns over the years is not having a significant relationship with count numbers. However, this is not true for changes in temperature and rainfall patterns. The results show that the higher counts for Hooded Plover observed in unseasonably hot and wetter periods are falling in recent years. This study shows that statistical models can be used to address the challenges associated with monitoring the persistence of rare birds, while identifying factors affecting this persistence such as climate. However, the accuracy of the citizen science data used is a limitation for this study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effect of ecoregions for Australian resident shorebirds in the context of seasonal migration using citizen science data</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/eco/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/eco/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Ecoregions are natural zones that feature separate collections of plants and animals because they have climatic homogeneity - the same temperature, amount of rainfall, and humidity. An ecoregion is the only unit that is small enough to be noticeable but large enough to be significant. An ecoregion encompasses a larger physical area than an ecosystem or habitat and it may contain hundreds of ecosystems and several habitats. Ecoregions are significant to conservationists because they contain places with critical ecological and evolutionary processes and circumstances. Although tropical rainforests and coral reefs harbour the most biodiversity, unique manifestations of nature can be found in all other ecoregions, which may be lost forever if they are not safeguarded and conserved. In this study we have analysed the effect of ecoregions for resident shorebirds in Australia in the context of local migration. In this study we considered count data for Masked Lapwing, Banded Stilt, Black-winged Stilt, Red-capped Dotterel, Red-kneed Dotterel and Red-necked Avocet, taken from Atlas of Living Australia (ALA) for the years 2000 to 2018 at a seasonal level across the whole of Australia. We have fitted spatio-temporal models with besagproper latent models in INLA, taking ecoregions of each bioregion, season and trend into account.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The first set of models considers only main effects for trend, season and ecoregion, finding significant variation in counts across the seasons for all the species. However, significant differences in counts across the seven ecoregions were only found for the Black-winged Stilt, the Masked Lapwing and Red-Capped Dotterel. A significant upward trend in the counts for Masked Lapwing and Red-Capped Dotterel was also identified. The second set of models consider seasonal migration across ecoregions while controlling for trend, finding significant seasonal migration for all the species. The final set of models considered changes in the ecoregion distribution across the years while controlling for seasonal migration. This model suggested a decreasing trend for Banded-Stilt with no significant differences in this trend across the ecoregions. For all the other regions there were significant differences in trend across the ecoregions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Possible biases in the citizen science data used in this study is one limitation of this study. In addition, our models are intended to describe only long-term trends in seasonal migration, and they do not allow for the sporadic flooding of wetlands in particular years. It is expected that wetland bird counts are under-estimated in these years because it is hard to reach these areas due to flooded roads. Also, the length of the series used in this analysis is too short to allow for El Nino cycles. Future models should attempt to take this into consideration while also investigating the reasons for increasing counts in some ecoregions and decreasing counts in other ecoregions.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a follow-up to this study, examined the effects of ecoregions on biodiversity over time (with the same six inland resident shorebirds) using spatiotemporal models.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Effectiveness of the conservation areas on the Mornington Peninsula for the resident shorebird species using citizen science data</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/lsa/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/lsa/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Conservation areas are a key strategy for preserving biodiversity, but few citizen science studies have evaluated the effectiveness of this strategy. In the absence of comprehensive survey data this study used citizen science records of annual data for seven resident shorebirds for the Mornington Peninsula from 2010 to 2019 extracted from the Atlas of Living Australia, to assess which species were most likely to be threatened by climate variability and which species benefit most from protected areas. This was done by fitting temporal models using the Integrated Laplace Approximation (INLA) method. We examined temporal models using Poisson and Negative Binomial distributions and determined that the Poisson distribution provides the best fit, as measured by the lowest Deviance Information Criterion (DIC).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The trends for seven resident shorebird species were compared to the Australian Pied Oystercatcher, with significantly steeper upward trends identified for the Black-fronted Dotterel, Red-capped Dotterel and Red-kneed Dotterel. Steeper upward trends were observed in conservation than other areas for the Black-fronted Dotterel, Masked Lapwing and Red-kneed Dotterel.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The results for the Dotterel species in conservation areas are particularly encouraging. This work suggests that, with some limitations, statistical models can be used with citizen science data for monitoring the persistence of resident shorebirds and for investigating factors that are impacting these data.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Mathematical models for predicting debt repayment</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/debt/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/debt/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Debt collection is a massive industry, with in USA alone more than $50 billion recovered each year.
However, the information available is often limited and incomplete, and predicting whether a given
debtor would repay is inherently a challenging task. This has amplified research on debt recovery
classification and prediction models of late. This research considered three main mathematical, data
mining and statistical models in debt recovery classification, in logistic regression, artificial neural
networks and affinity analysis. It also compares the effectiveness of the above mentioned tools in
evaluating whether a debt is likely to be repaid. The construction and analysis of the models were
based on a fairly large unbalanced data sample provided by a debt collection agency. We have shown
that all three models could classify the debt repayments with a considerable accuracy, if the
assumptions of the models are satisfied.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Modelling the recovery of local shorebirds using citizen science data following a fox eradication program</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/chgp/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/chgp/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;In the past fox predation was the greatest land-based threat for shorebird colonies on Phillip Island, Victoria, Australia. Regular fox control for 20 years reduced the fox population, but shorebirds and seabirds including the Little Penguin continued to be decimated. Therefore, a fox eradication program was started in 2006, with three phases called knock-down, clean-up and post-eradication. An effective knock-down was declared in 2011, heralding the start of the clean-up phase.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The impact of fox eradication on resident shorebirds has never been thoroughly assessed in this context. This study aims to track the recovery of six resident shorebird species found on Phillip Island including the locally threatened Hooded Plover and Sooty Oystercatcher. The methods used break new ground for assessing the recovery of bird species populations during a successful pest eradication program. We have used citizen science data for 2003 to 2017, extracted from the Atlas of Living Australia. The first analysis method used is INLA modelling assuming a Negative Binomial distribution for bird counts, in order to test for upward trends in shorebird numbers during the fox eradication program. The second method involves changepoint analyses to test whether the successive phases of the eradication process relate to changes in bird count levels.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Five of the six shorebird species considered exhibited a significant positive response to reduced fox numbers over this period and all changepoint methods consistently identified the start of the clean-up phase with less consistency in the case of the start of the knock-down phase. The INLA models suggest a significant increase in the upward trend for the number of shorebirds since 2006 for three of the species considered. The fox eradication program was shown to be beneficial for all the species except the Black-winged Stilt. Agreement in the changepoints identified by the four changepoint methods suggests that for all these shorebird species, changes in bird numbers were linked to the timing of the clean-up phase of the eradication program. These methods show some promise for monitoring the recovery of native species during conservation programs; however, the use of citizen science data is a serious limitation of this study.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Optimal Distribution Schedule for Lunar Clothing Manufacturing Company in Sri Lanka</title>
      <link>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/opti/</link>
      <pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://udaniwijewardhana.github.io/project/opti/</guid>
      <description>&lt;p&gt;Lunar Clothing is a business enterprise which manufactures clothes for vendors who operates in six provinces named Western, Southern, Central, North West, North Central and Sabaragamuwa. Each province has a single hub and each hub has six clothing stores located in different places in particular province. Clothes are distributed to the vendors according to their request. Main store is located at Negombo free trade zone in Western province. The main objective of this study is to generate an optimal distribution schedule to minimize the total transportation cost. To achieve this, we considered three conditions such as size of the item requested by the vendors, the weather conditions of the local roads and the distance between the hubs and the vendors.The Lunar Clothing problem is one of the complex situations in shortest path Algorithm. This study is about the usage of traveling salesman algorithm for real world scenario. The entire problem has been decomposed to four major tasks such as dispatching the truck from main store to provincial hubs, assigning vendors for six stores in each provincial hub, transporting clothes from provincial hubs to vendors and dispatching ships to foreign ports. Then each and every task was analyzed and solved by using relevant algorithm. For mathematical modeling part and to generate the solution, Lingo software has been used. Some assumptions have been done in tasks for simplification. Then the optimal distribution schedule for Lunar Clothing has been implemented for processes in both inside and outside the country.&lt;/p&gt;
</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
